and what about the acne is it your
experience that you see a lot of men
getting acne in the beginning of their
trt early on I mean I did I think you
know I noticed the first even couple
weeks when I started trt my GRE my skin
was oilier um you could wipe your
forehead and just be greased but then
after about four or six weeks it kind of
stabilized for me um I don't have a lot
of issues with acne with as far as
percentage of my patients it seems like
or at least I don't hear about about it
the ones that are truly bothered by it
or having some really big like cystic
acne type problems I will hear about and
those guys more times than not we're
able to uh they're usually on injections
and we're usually able to switch the
carrier oil around to clear up their
skin quite a bit I've had a lot of guys
doing commercial cotton seed oil sesame
oil preparations and we get them on
either grape seed or or MCT oil I prefer
MCT oil if we can get it for them just
seems to be a lot cleaner and lo and
behold six weeks go by and their skin
you know they message me like hey Doc my
Skin's clearing up I'm like yeah because
you're not injecting you know
everybody's different with how their
body responds to those things well
you're injecting seed oils into your
body you're probably gonna stimulate
some inflammatory response if the body
like that so now when it comes to like
hormonal acne quote unquote um man
that's a that's a trickier one because
some guys it seems like no matter what
you give them a little testosterone
whether it's cream or injections they
just get acne and
I'm not a you know I'm not going to tell
them no you you know don't take acutane
or don't do this or that um I'll just I
want them to be informed with the risks
of that I mean we know that they're
again it's the same thing with taking
something for your hair you have to be
willing to accept a tradeoff usually and
I think a lot of guys just aren't people
in general don't like that they want
everything to work the way they want it
to and it just doesn't work like that
there just seems to be tradeoffs um
opportunity cost essentially um but yeah
for acne I would always tell guys you
know we we see these posts in the group
a lot um the first thing to look at is
if you're on injections what kind of oil
are you using what frequency of your
dosing all that um if you're on cream a
lot of guys just you know we'll check a
level and their free free testosterone's
50 or higher it's like okay we may want
to I know you feel good but may want to
drop your dose down just a little you
you may still feel fine but it may clear
up the acne a little bit and then also
with acne as you know you they've got to
look at every other thing they're
putting in their body they've got to
look at their diet they've got to look
at their metabolic Health um all those
all those things apply other medicines
they may be taken so it's not just a
onetick pony when it comes to acne I
know a lot of people want to blame it on
the hormone but it's not always that
straightforward obviously when you start
a new hormone and you get acne it's like
pretty obvious okay that probably caused
it but you don't know if it's the
hormone that caused it or something else
in the preparation especially with
injections so just and test different
variables yeah exactly I see in our
group a lot of people ask me about
acutane a lot of them are afraid about
it they compare it to the side effects
from finasteride but that's not really
the case there's U yeah I I've
prescribed isotretinoin because that's
the the generic name the molecule
acutane is brand name here it's even
called row acutane um so uh if you might
through those it's 10 20 milligram a day
the side effects aren't that bad at all
except maybe for some dry lips for but
uh next to that there almost close to
nothing really yeah yeah everybody
tolerates it different you know I've had
some people yeah they they have just a
little bit of dry and other people look
like they're losing fish scales off
their face you know but that's usually
probably a dose response relationship
there it's very dose dependent that